

JULIO NODA

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT AND JAVA DEVELOPER

I'm a Java architect, analyst and developer, with more than 15 years of experience making software, mostly building custom web applications. With great teamwork abilities, assuming tasks with initiative and autonomy. I have excellent aptitudes for finding technological solutions.







LANGUAGE

Spanish

English

SKILLS

Web Applications

Software Architecture

Design Patterns

TECHNOLOGIES

Java

Spring Framework

Hibernate ORM

Maven

Amazon Web Services

HTML & CSS

Javascript

HOBBIES













WORK EXPERIENCE

Present

Java Full-Stack Developer Speexx

Reworked legacy applications, with modern frameworks and technologies. Developed integrations with third-party solutions (Workable, Microsoft Teams, Microsoft Dynamics 365). Researched integration path to other solutions (Cornerstone OnDemand, SCIM with Azure AD, xAPI). Defined coding and testing guidelines for the development team. Promoted changes to development processes with DevOps, automatic testing and quality tools.

2014 - 2018

Software Architect and Senior Java Developer Webtools S.L.

Designed, developed, maintained and improved e-encuesta.com; a platform hosted in the cloud to create online surveys, scalable and with high availability. Comprised by a set of distributed applications built with a classic Java 8 stack supported by the infrastructure provided by Amazon Web Services.

2012 - 2014

Software Architect and Senior Java Developer Resolution Art Inc.

Expansion and improvement of the support infrastructure initially created for Gixcel Canada Inc. Personalized a workflow execution engine based on jBPM for the management of business processes. Used Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud to automate the dynamic and efficient execution of tasks requiring intensive use of processing power and memory. Used Amazon's services to fulfill the needs of information storage for the company at short, medium and long term.

2010 - 2012

Software Architect and Senior Java Developer Gixcel Canada Inc.

Designed, developed and maintained a support infrastructure for Gixcel Canada Inc.; a company specialized on the digitization in ultra-high definition and printing of two dimensional works of art. This infrastructure is formed by:

- A corporate website, a virtual store and a portal that targets enthusiasts and professionals of visual arts. Developed as a personalization of Liferay Portal; supported by the hosting and storage services provided by Amazon.
- A group of systems and internal modules for production support developed using a classic Java stack; running in Apache Tomcat server on Linux.

EDUCATION



Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), Computer Science Universidad de La Habana

Courses covering topics on software development, mathematics and applied mathematics. Several awards on Scientific Sessions organized by the faculty. Contributions for the Metaheuristics' Research Team on genetic algorithms.

SECTOR KNOWLEDGE

- ✓ Agile Methodologies
- ✓ Data Structures
- ✓ Databases
- ✓ Design Patterns
- ✓ Graphic Design

- ✓ Object Oriented Programming
- ✓ Project Management
- ✓ Requirement Analysis
- ✓ Software Architecture
- ✓ Software Design

- ✓ Software Development
- ✓ Software Engineering
- ✓ Test Driven Development
- ✓ Web Applications
- ✓ Web Services

TOOLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

- ✓ Atlassian Suite
- ✓ AJAX
- ✓ Amazon Web Services
- ✓ Apache
- ✓ Apache Tomcat
- ✓ Bootstrap
- ✓ CSS
- ✓ Eclipse IDE
- ✓ EclipseLink
- ✓ Firebird
- ✓ Git

- ✓ Hibernate ORM
- ✓ HTML
- ✓ IntelliJ IDEA
- Java
- ✓ Java Server Pages (JSP)
- ✓ JavaScript
- ✓ JPA
- ✓ jQuery
- ✓ JSON
- ✓ JUnit
- Linux

- ✓ Maven
- ✓ Mockito
- ✓ MySQL
- ✓ Polymer
- **✓** REST
- ✓ Spring Framework
- **✓** SQL
- ✓ Thymeleaf
- ✓ UML
- ✓ XML

MORE INFO



For more information (experience, courses, recommendations, etc) www.julionoda.com